Okay, finally...
（ナツキ･スバル）はい 最後に―
Victory!
ビクトリー
（村人一同）ビクトリー
All right, line up!
（スバル）
よーし 並べ 並べ
Yay!
Time for your stamps!
スタンプ押すぞー
Okay, who's first?
よーし １番は誰だ？
The kitty's so cute!
（ペトラ）猫ちゃん かわいい
The kitty's awesome!
（リュカ）猫ちゃん ステキ
The kitty's so sad!
（ミルド）猫ちゃん 不憫(ふびん)
Looks like the villagers are full of life again.
（エミリア）
村の人たちも すっかり
元気になったみたいで
Thanks to you, Subaru.
スバルのおかげね
Well, I did put my life on the line to save them.
まあ 俺も今回 みんなのために―
それはもう 体を張って
頑張ったからな
I went into the forest and got
chewed on by dogs to save the kids,
子供たちを助けに
森に入って―
犬に噛(か)まれ
got chewed on some more when I tried to
save Rem after she turned into a demon,
鬼化したレムを
助けようとして―
犬に噛まれ
then Roswaal saved me right as I was
about to become a giant dog's chew toy...
最後に また
強大化した犬に―
噛まれそうなところを
ロズワールに助けられ…
あれ？
Wait...
Did I actually do anything?
俺 思ったよりも
何もしてなくない？
Honestly, there's no need to
fuss over the small details!
もう
そうやって
つまらないこと気にしないの
There are people who know the full truth.
分かってる人たちは
ちゃんと分かってるもの
That includes Roswaal and Ram.
ロズワールだって
ラムだって―
And especially Rem.
レムなんか 特にそう
And of course,
それに もちろん
私だってそうなんだから
I do too.
A dragon carriage?
（スバル）おっ 竜車
Welcome home.
（ヴィルヘルム･
ヴァン･アストレア）
お帰りなさいませ
Please forgive me for parking
in front of your mansion.
ただいま 屋敷の前を
失礼させて頂いております
An emissary is visiting from the capital.
（ラム）
王都から 使者の方が
お見えになっています
Roswaal-sama is attending to them now.
ロズワール様が
応対なさっていますが―
Please join him, Emilia-sama.
エミリア様もご同席ください
An emissary?
使者って…
I believe it concerns the royal selection.
王選に関してのことかと
All right.
よし さすがに事が事だけに
バカやらねえようにしねえと
Given the circumstances,
I'll try not to do anything stupid.
Um, I'm really sorry, Subaru,
えっと…
スバルには悪いんだけど―
but this will be a very important discussion.
ここから先は
大事はお話だから
Aren't you bored waiting out here?
（スバル）
ずーっと表で待ってるのも
退屈しませんか？
It tastes lovely.
いい味です
I feel as though I'm indulging in a great luxury.
かなり奮発されたものと思いますが
No kidding. It's the most
expensive tea in the mansion.
マジに この屋敷で
１番高い茶です
If the pink-haired maid finds out
we drank it without permission, she'll flip.
勝手に飲んだのがバレたら―
桃色の髪のメイドが
マジギレするぐらい
（ヴィルヘルム）
で そのようなお茶をまき餌に
この老骨に何をお求めですかな
And what is it you hope to gain
from buttering up this old man
with such precious bait?
I only want to know the reason for this visit.
今日の訪問の
理由が知りたいんです
If you could just pass me a tiny little hint...
さわりだけでも結構ですので
As I have no idea what your
standing is in this mansion,
あなたが屋敷で どんな立場に
あるか分からない私には―
I cannot afford to speak carelessly.
うかつなことを
口にすることはできませんな
I beg your understanding.
ご理解を
However, I did see that you
are quite close to Emilia-sama.
ただ―
エミリア様と親しい間柄なのは
うかがえましたな
Did it look like things were serious
between Emilia-tan and me!?
俺とエミリアたんが
ただならぬ関係に見えました？
アハハハハ…
（ヴィルヘルム）“たん”？
"Tan"?
It is a steep path you climb.
険しい道を行きますな
You are chasing after someone who may
very well be Lugunica's future queen.
相手は ルグニカの次期女王に
なるかもしれないお方ですよ
Right now, we're just a super cute girl
and a useless servant boy.
現状は ただの超かわいい女の子と
さえない使用人ってだけです
I bet your wife was the prettiest
girl in the world to you.
御者さんは 奥さんは
世界一かわいいかもしれない
Isn't that what you thought
when you proposed to her?
そう思いながら 結婚を
申し込んだりしなかったんですか？
My wife...
妻は…
I understand. You are very correct.
なるほど　あなたの言うとおりだ
I believed my wife the most
beautiful lady in the world.
私も妻が世界一美しいと
思っていました
I'm back, Old Man Wil!
（フェリックス･アーガイル）
ただいま ヴィル爺(じい)
Sorry you had to wait out here.
外で待たせちゃってごめんね
退屈だったでしょう
I bet you were bored, huh?
Not at all.
This young man here has been
keeping me company.
こちらの方が 老骨の話相手に
なってくださいましたので
はみゃ？
はみゃみゃ？
はみゃ
Ah, nyow I see. That makes sense.
ああ にゃるほど そっかそっか
You must be the boy Emilia-sama mentioned.
君が エミリア様の言ってた
男の子なのね？
Emilia did?
エミリアが？
I guess you know nyothing at all, huh?
にゃんも聞かされて
ないみたいだね
Let's go, Old Man Wil.
行こう ヴィル爺
See you in the capital.
王都で会おうね
Just so you know, we aren't going for fun.
あのね 遊びに行くわけじゃないの
I received an important summons—
大事な呼び出しがあって…
If it's important, all the more reason!
（スバル）
大事なことなら なおさらだ
It's related to the royal selection, right?
I want to be there for you!
王選絡みなんだろ？
俺は エミリアたんの
助けになりてえんだ
Please!
頼む！
（レム）
王都には スバルくんが
お世話になった方々も―
It seems there are people in
the capital who helped Subaru-kun.
いらっしゃるみたいですし―
This may be a good opportunity
for him to thank them.
この機会に
お礼に伺うのもよいかと
Nice assist, Rem!
ナイスアシスト レム
That's right!
そうなんだよ
Some people in the capital helped me.
王都には世話になった奴らがいる
顔見せて安心させてやらねえと
I need to let them know I'm okay.
I don't see why not.
（ロズワール･Ｌ･メイザース）
いーんじゃないかい？
That can be kept separate from
our royal selection business.
王選うんぬんてーのとは
別のお話で
Subaru-kun should go to
the capital to thank everyone,
スバルくんが王都に行くのは
お礼参りと それにもう１つ―
as well as to receive treatment.
治療目的ってーことで
Huh? Treatment?
は？ 治療？
You overused your already-exhausted gate in the witchfiend battle.
魔獣との戦いで 枯渇した
ゲートを酷使したかーらね
Treatment to tend that wound.
その傷の治療
You met the emissary earlier, did you not?
スバルくんは
さっきの使者には会ったかな？
The cutesy-face with the cat ears?
あの猫耳ぶりっ子か？
That was one of the capital's most
brilliant users of water magic,
あの子が王都でも
とびっきり優秀な水の魔法―
as well as healing magic!
治癒魔法の使い手だーよ
But that comes with its share of eccentricities.
クセのある子だから
協力を取り付けるのには―
Even Emilia-sama had difficulty
winning over that brilliance.
エミリア様も苦労された
もんなんだからねーえ
Hey...
ちょっと…
Really, Emilia-tan?
エミリアたん マジで？
You did that for me?
俺のために？
W-Well, it's partly my fault
that you haven't healed yet.
（エミリア）
だ… だって スバルの
体が治らないのは―
私のせいでもあるもん
So you could say I'm repaying a debt.
だから これは恩返しっていうか
損失に対する正当な補填(ほてん)なの！
It's compensation equal to what you gave up!
I'm surprised you were talking with that boy.
（フェリックス）
ヴィル爺が
あの子とお話してたのが―
意外だったかな
I thought you more likely to chop people in half than talk to them.
人と話すより
ぶった斬っちゃうほうが好きなのに
That is a grave misunderstanding.
ひどい誤解ですな
I merely took a bit of a liking
to that young man's eyes.
あの少年の目が少しばかり
気になっただけです
Those are the eyes of a man
well-versed with death.
（ヴィルヘルム）
あれは 何度か
死域に踏み込んだ者の目です
Hmm, you've lost me nyow.
ふーん よく分かんにゃい
But if Wilhelm van Astrea,
the Sword Demon, says it,
でも―
剣鬼(けんき) ヴィルヘルム･
ヴァン･アストレアが―
そこまで言うんだから―
I'm sure that boy travels quite a bumpy road.
きっと平たんな道は歩けないよね
あの子
You know, Emilia-tan...
（スバル）
あのさ エミリアたん
Maybe we should stop this?
これやっぱりやめねえ？
Absolutely not!
絶対にダーメ！
I know you.
スバルのことだから―
The moment I look away,
you'll be doing something crazy.
目を離した隙に
おかしなことするに決まってる
Oh, man! I'm seriously moved!
ヤッバイ すごい感動がある！
I'm totally fantasying right now, baby!
超ファンタジーしてるんばらばー！
Subaru-kun is cute.
スバルくん かわいい
Fantasy worlds rul—
異世界最高ー！
アババババ…
（エミリア）スバル！
Subaru!
I'm really sorry for that.
あれは超反省してるよ
でも 扱いがガキすぎるって これ…
But this is treating me like a kid!
Even though you wanted to hold
hands on our date in the village?
村でデイトした時は
あんなにつなぎたがってたのに？
I was physically and mentally prepared for that.
（スバル）
あん時は 心と体の
準備が万端だったけど―
This time, I'm not!
今はできてないの
手汗すごいの
My hand's sweating like crazy!
Would you two quit it with the flirting already?
（カドモン･リッシュ）
いいかげん イチャつくのは
その辺にしとけや
You're gonna drive away my customers.
客が寄りつかなくなんだろうが
That's what I get for coming
to make good on my promise?
せっかく約束を果たそうって
来たのに つれねえなあ
That's cold, man...
Well, I appreciate that you felt obliged to shop,
now that you're not broke anymore.
まあ 無一文でなくなって―
義理堅く 買い物に来たってのは
ありがてえがな
Here are the appas I promised.
ほれ 約束のリンガだ
Next, it's Felt and Old Man Rom.
（スバル）
次はフェルトとロム爺だな
I thought we'd wrapped things
up cleanly the first time.
（エミリア）
最初は おとがめなしってことで
話はまとまったんだけど―
But then Reinhard's expression went dark,
ラインハルトが 急に顔色を変えて
女の子を連れてっちゃって…
and he took the girl away.
That makes it sound like kidnapping,
or an abduction and confinement.
それだけ聞くと 誘拐犯か
拉致監禁魔なんだけど
Hot guys sure get special treatment...
イケメンは得だよなあ
If we want to contact Reinhard,
ラインハルトと
連絡を取るなら―
we should probably go to the guard station
in front of the Nobles' Quarter.
貴族街の手前にある 衛兵の
詰め所に行くのがいいと思うの
Emilia-tan, about the royal selection
that begins tomorrow...
エミリアたん 明日からある
王選の話なんだけどさ…
スバル
Subaru,
what did I tell you?
言ったでしょ
スバルを王都に連れてきたのは―
I brought you here to fulfill your
promises and to get you healed.
いろんな約束を
守らせてあげるためなのと―
スバルの体の治療のため
You don't have to worry about me.
私のことは気にしないでいいの
Well, if it isn't Emilia-sama.
（ユリウス･ユークリウス）
これは エミリア様
It's good to see you again.
お久しぶりです
その後 お変わりはありませんか？
Have you been well since we last met?
Yes, everything is basically the same.
ええ 特に変わりないわ
You also seem well, Julius.
ユリウスも元気そうで
The mere fact that you
remember me is an honor.
（ユリウス）
覚えて頂いてるだけで光栄です
You have only grown more
beautiful, Emilia-sama.
エミリア様も その美しさは
一層を増すばかりで
Thank you.
ありがとう
Forgive me for asking so abruptly,
いきなりで悪いんだけど
ちょっと用事があって―
but I have business here, and I'd like you
to act as my agent in the castle.
お城の方に
取り次いでもらいたいの
Does your business involve this young man?
用件とは そちらの彼と関係が？
フン
His character and attitude poorly suit his attire.
服装に見合わない品性と態度だ
That's no way to act before one you've just met.
初対面の相手に
見せる姿ではないな
Thanks for the warning!
ご忠告感謝だ
I've got a warning of my own for you.
俺のほうからも
１個だけ忠告してやる
You shouldn't eat curry udon in that suit.
その格好でカレーうどん
食べるのは―
If the soup splatters,
the stains will really stand out.
汁がはねたら目立つから
やめたほうがいいぜ
I don't know what "curry udon" is,
カレーうどんとは
何か分からないが―
気にかけることにしよう
but I shall keep that in mind.
Now, allow me to show you
to the conference mirrors.
では 対話鏡へご案内しましょう
Conference mirrors?
対話鏡？
A metia that facilitates talking with someone,
using two mirrors facing one another.
対になっている鏡どうしで―
映した相手と会話ができる
ミーティアなの
Ah, mirrors... How very magical.
（スバル）
なーる 鏡とは魔法っぽい
Subaru, wait here.
スバルは待ってて
Huh?
I don't think it would be
a pleasant experience for you.
（エミリア）
きっと スバルがイヤな思いを
すると思うから
I've already had an experience
as unpleasant as it gets.
（スバル）
イヤな思いなら
すでに十分したんですけど
That bastard, licking all over your cute,
little hand, as if he owned it...
気安くエミリアたんのかわいい手を
ベロベロなめまわしやがって くっ
I'll try not to let things drag on too long.
あまり長引かせないようにして
戻ってくるから―
Be good and wait, okay?
いい子で待ってて
Please?
お願いよ
（スバル）ハア…
I look so pathetic.
俺 超かっこ悪(わり)い
Right in front of the guard station?
Now that's bold.
詰め所前で大胆な犯行
"The darkest place is under the candlestick," I guess.
灯台もと暗しというやつか？
You little...
（トン）てめえ
Don't screw around with us!
（チン）
ふざけてんじゃねえぞ！
Want us to mess up that pretty face of yours?
（カン）
そのきれいな顔を
ふっとばしてやろうか？
Don't make such a racket, commoners.
（プリシラ･バーリエル）
やいやい騒ぐでない 凡愚(ぼんぐ)
Fools with no character pick fights
for the most foolish of reasons...
品性の足りん やからは
因縁のつけ方にも品がないのう
Sorry I'm late, honey!
（スバル）
待たせてごめんな ハニー
It appears there's been a bit of trouble.
ちょっとトラブルが
あったみたいだけど―
But I'm here now,
so please cut me some slack.
どうか 俺に免じて
勘弁してくれ
Now, let's go.
さっ 行こうぜ
Do not touch me so familiarly!
妾(わらわ)に気安く触れるでない！
Cliffhanger...
（スバル）クリフハンガー…
I don't want drooling commoners
to follow me around.
凡愚風情が よだれを垂らして
妾につきまとうな
Read between the lines a bit, will you!?
（スバル）
話の流れ つかめよ！
It was supposed to be a classic scenario
where I save a girl from hoodlums!
チンピラから女の子を助け出す時の
黄金パターンだったろうが
Wait, no way.
何 ウソ？
Are you three the capital's only hoodlums?
王都って お前らしか
チンピラいないの？
We met this guy in the alley
behind the shopping district.
こいつ 前に商い通りの路地で…
It's the brat from back then?
あの時のガキか
So, for my sake, could you just let us—
それじゃあ ここは
俺の顔に免じて見逃して…
Are you dumb?
バカかお前 ３対１が３対２に
なっただけじゃねえかよ
This just makes it three on two,
instead of three on one.
You should correct that.
（プリシラ）訂正せい
It isn't three on two,
but three on one on one.
３対２ではなく
３対１対１じゃ
Would you be quiet for a second!?
お前ちょっと
黙っててくれる？
Looks like I have no choice.
しかたねえ この手だけは
使いたくなかったんだが…
This is the last trick I wanted to use, but...
Just sayin', me and Reinhard-san
are pretty close, y'know?
言っとくが 俺はラインハルトさん
知ってんだぞ おら
One small word from me,
and he'll be here in a flash.
俺が呼んだら
すぐビューンて飛んでくるぜ
Secret Technique: Fox in Tiger's Clothing.
（スバル）
秘義 虎の威を借る狐(きつね)
Been a while since I've seen you.
久々に見かけたと思えば
お前さん 何をやっとるんじゃ
What're ya doing here?
ハッ ロム爺
Old Man Rom!
（トン･チン･カン）
チクショウ 覚えてろよー
Damn you!
We'll make you regret this!
ハア…
Nice save, Old Man Rom.
助かったぜ ロム爺
I doubt this girl and I could've handled that alone.
俺とこの子だけじゃ
ヤバかったかもしれねえとこだった
Make no mistake.
勘違いするでない
Even without you two, I was in no trouble.
別に 貴様らがおらずとも
妾には何の問題もなかった
Say what?
どういうこと？
"I didn't need your help.
I'm super strong! I was doing just fine!"
別に 助けてもらわなくても
妾様は超強いんだから―
全然平気だったんだからね
Something like that?
みたいなこと？
No.
違う
This world is designed to operate
in the way that works best for me,
この世界は 妾の都合の
よいようにできておる
so I am never at a disadvantage.
故に 妾に不利益は起こらん
R-Really?
そ… そっか…
Well, I shouldn't have butted in, then.
それは 余計なマネして悪かった
ジャマしてごめんちゃい
Sorry to interfere!
By the way, boy,
ところで小僧 フェルトが
どこに行ったか知らんか？
you know where Felt went off to?
You didn't hear?
聞いてねえのか？
Apparently, Reinhard took her away.
ラインハルトの奴が
連れていったって話だけど
Reinhard...
ラインハルト…
It had to be an Astrea, eh?
よりによって アストレア家か
Something wrong?
（スバル）どうかしたんか？
Nah, just talkin' to myself.
いや こっちの話じゃ
You try not to cause any more trouble, ya hear?
お前さんは もう
騒ぎを起こさんようにな
S-Sure.
（エミリア）やっと見つけた
I finally found you!
Oh, Emili—
あっ エミリ…
Wait, wait, wait!
待て待て待て！
You can't just pick up
Emilia-tan while I'm away!
俺のいない間に エミリアたん
ナンパしてんじゃねえ！
Seems your buddy's got
a screw loose, little lady.
（アルデバラン）
嬢ちゃんの連れ
かなりネジ飛んでんな
More worried about losing you
to another man than happy to see you.
再会の喜びより
泥棒猫の心配とか―
A man's heart is so complex,
it's a thrill to watch.
男心複雑すぎて
見ててワクワクすんよ
You've got a pretty messed-up
fashion sense of your own!
そういうお前も
相当ファッションセンスやべえな
Now, that's no way to talk to someone.
（アルデバラン）
口の利き方がなってねえぜ？
As I'm a cool, good-natured man, I'll overlook it.
俺が渋くて気のいいおっさんだから
許してやっけど―
But some might lop off your head for that.
相手次第じゃ首チョンパだ
Relax, Subaru. His outfit surprised me too.
安心して スバル
この人の格好に驚いたのは
私も同じだから
Yeah, well...
（アルデバラン）まあな
I was surprised when she offered to help me
while I was looking for a lost child too.
迷子捜し中の
俺につきあってくれるとか―
言い出したのは
こっちもびっくりだけどよ
Emilia-tan, you're too soft-hearted.
エミリアたん お人好しすぎ
Dressed like that, most people would think
he's trying to kidnap a child, not find one.
普通に考えて
こいつの この格好―
迷子捜して誘拐するタイプだろ
My, how diligent you are to wait
where you knew I would end up.
（プリシラ）
うむ 妾の行く先で待つとは
なかなか気が回る
I commend your dedication, Al.
殊勝な心がけじゃな アル
You were the lost child?
迷子ってあんたかよ
Well, it looks like we both found
who we were looking for. See ya.
あんじゃ お互い捜し人は
見つかったみたいだし 行くか
Wait.
（プリシラ）待つがいい
What is in that bag?
その袋の中身は何じゃ？
They're appas.
リンガだよ 見たことねえのか？
You've never seen one?
Don't make me laugh.
笑わせるでない
リンガは白い実の果実じゃ
Appas have white flesh.
Well, yeah, the insides are white...
そりゃ中身は白いけどな…
W-Wait, so you've never
seen an unpeeled appa?
まさか 皮むく前のリンガ
見たことねえの？
For you.
やるよ
Don't skip off after any bad guys again, okay?
今後は 悪い大人に
ふらふらついてくんじゃねえぞ
Subaru...
（エミリア）
スバル さっきの女の子とは…
That girl from before...
Huh?
Where did you meet that girl?
さっきの女の子とは どこで？
And how?
どうして？
え？ なになに
エミリアたん 嫉妬？
What's this, Emilia-tan? Are you jealous?
Are you actually getting jealous over me?
やきもちとかやいてくれちゃった
感じの展開… と
Subaru...
（エミリア）スバル
H-Huh? Emilia-tan, why the serious face?
なっ… あれ… エミリアたん
そんなマジ顔で何を？
N-Nothing... If you don't know, it's fine.
（エミリア）
あ… ううん
知らないならいいの 忘れて
Forget it.
Oh! It really is an appa!
おお 確かに これはリンガじゃ
Huh? I have to stay here tomorrow?
（スバル）
え？ 明日はお留守番？
Of course you do.
当たり前じゃない
もともと その約束だったでしょ？
That was our agreement all along.
Yeah, but we never reached Reinhard, right?
けど ラインハルトには
結局連絡つかなかったんだろ？
So if we go to the castle
tomorrow, we might see him...
だったら 明日は王城に行けば
会えるかもだし…
I'll be sure to ask about Felt.
（エミリア）
フェルトのことは
私が必ず聞いておくから
But I should go in person to—
いや でも そこは俺が直接…
This is exactly why I can't take you with me.
（エミリア）
そんなだから
連れていけないって言ってるの
If I do, you'll push yourself too hard again.
スバルを連れていったら
また無理するに決まってるもの
I don't want to let you do that. Understand?
そんなことさせたくないの
分かって
You're the one who doesn't understand...
エミリアたんこそ
分かってねえよ
If that's what it takes to help you, so be it!
俺が無理して―
それでエミリアたんの
助けになるなら いいんだよ
I want to push myself!
俺は無理がしてえんだ
絶対にダメ
Absolutely not.
Until your body is fully healed,
体がきちんと治るまで
魔法はもちろん 無理も禁止
no using magic or pushing yourself!
Promise me, Subaru.
約束して スバル
All right. I promise.
分かった 約束するよ
I won't use magic.
魔法は使わねえ
だからな 俺も一緒に…
So let me go with you!
I can't bring an outsider into this.
（エミリア）
部外者は入れられないの
So please wait here with Rem, all right?
だからお願い レムと一緒に
おとなしく待っていて
Please, Subaru...
お願いだから スバル
私を信じさせて
Give me reason to trust you.
（スバル）王都には
I know there are those in the capital
who consider Emilia an enemy.
エミリアに敵意を持つ奴が
絶対にいやがる
That's why I have to stay close to her.
だから 俺がそばに
ついててやらねえと
What's the matter?
（レム）
どうしたんですか？
I'm going to help Emilia.
エミリアを助ける
And to do that...
そのためにも…
Stare...
Wh-What is it, Subaru-kun?
な… 何ですか スバルくん
When you stare at me so intensely,
it makes me uncomfortable.
そんなりりしい目で見つめられると
困ってしまいます
Stare...
（レム）ハア…
場所は王城
警備は万全と思いますけど
It's at the castle.
I would imagine security will be very heavy.
Security isn't the problem.
（スバル）
警備の問題じゃねえんだよ
I can't stand not being involved
in Emilia's important affairs.
エミリアの大事に関われないのが
イヤなんだ
Subaru-kun...
スバルくん
I'm only of any use when something happens.
俺は 何かが起きた時しか
役に立たない
So I want to be with her when
important things are going on!
だから俺は 大事な時に
エミリアのそばにいたい
Now, I shall set about preparing
a new appa recipe I just thought up.
（レム）
今からレムは
急な思いつきで―
リンガを使った
新しい料理の開発に入ります
It will require intense concentration,
ものすごい集中力を
必要とするので―
so if one were to leave his room,
きっと 誰かが部屋を
抜け出したりしても―
I likely would not notice.
気づけない可能性が高いです
I'm such a scumbag for relying
on Rem all the time...
（スバル）
レムに甘えっぱなしの俺は最低だな
But the real problem is how
I'm gonna get into the castle.
（スバル）
けど 問題はどうやって
城の中に入るかだ
こういう時は
やっぱりあれか―
I guess times like this call for that...
Hitchhiking!
ヒッチハイク
You sure are lucky.
Be grateful that the stars aligned.
（アルデバラン）
ラッキーだったな 兄弟
偶然に感謝しな
It just so happens we were
on our way to the castle too.
俺らもちょうど
新しい向かう途中だったからよ
The castle? What for?
（スバル）王城？ 何しに
There is only one reason
to head to the castle today.
（プリシラ）
今日という日に
新しい向かう理由は ただ１つじゃ
Oh, you didn't know?
（アルデバラン）
あれ？ 知らなかったの？
This young lady here
こちらにおわす方こそ―
is one of the candidates
to succeed the throne of Lugunica,
ルグニカ王国
王位継承の候補者の１人―
Priscilla Barielle-sama herself.
プリシラ･バーリエル様 その人
For real? Then why did you pick me up?
マジかよ それが 何で俺を…
For no other reason than it seemed amusing.
（プリシラ）
興が乗った故の 戯れにすぎん
A mere lark.
余興のたぐいじゃ
Taking you to the castle
will make things interesting.
貴様を王城に引き連れて
行ったほうが―
面白いことになる
Interesting?
面白いって…
This world is designed to operate
in the way that works best for me,
（プリシラ）
この世の全ては 妾の
都合のよいようにできておる
so it is a given that all
things work in my favor.
故に あらゆる事柄の結果は―
妾に利するように決まっておる
It is only a matter of choosing
whether something amuses me or not.
ならば 興が乗るか 乗らぬか
それで選ぶだけじゃ
However, if I had to name
a reason other than amusement...
が １つ遊興以外に
理由があるとすれば―
Your appa handler?
（マーコス･ギルダーク）
リンガ係ですか
Indeed. He is something of a wretched clown,
（プリシラ）そうじゃ
妾に 赤く甘酸っぱい
リンガを献上することを―
whose sole priority is to bring me
bittersweet red appas.
至上の使命とした
あわれな道化のたぐいよ
（マーコス）フン…
Everyone is waiting inside.
皆様 中でお待ちです お急ぎを
Make haste, please.
As their superior, it is my privilege
to keep the masses waiting.
凡俗を待たせるのも 妾の優越よ
Subaru?
スバル…
Um... Emilia, I...
その エミリア 俺は…
Is there a reason you stare
at my manservant, half-wit?
妾の小間使いをじっと見て
何かあったか？ 半端物
Get off! You'll give Emilia-tan the wrong idea!
（スバル）
離れろ エミリアたんに誤解される
My, how nice to see you, Priscilla-sama!
（ロズワール）
これはこーれは プリシラ様
Do forgive my servant for troubling you so.
このたびは 当家の使用人が
とんだ迷惑を
（プリシラ）フン
どうして スバルがここにいるの？
Why are you here, Subaru?
Didn't I tell you to be good and wait for me?
言ったはずでしょ
おとなしく待っててって
Don't you remember?
覚えてないの？
The council of wise men will now enter.
（マーコス）
これより 賢人会の方々が
入場されます
The wise men...
賢人会って 確か
王様の代わりに―
They're the people managing
the country in place of the king, right?
国を運営とかしてる人たち
だったよな
Hey. That's where we're supposed to stand.
（アルデバラン）
よっ 俺らが並ぶのはあっちだぜ
I can stand there too?
俺も並んでいいのか？
Well, now...
そうだーねー 面白いから
そこの彼についてっていいよ
It sounds entertaining,
so you may accompany him.
Wait, Roswaal!
ちょっと ロズワール！
If Subaru is allowed to stay, he'll—
こんな場所に
同席させたら スバルが…
Emilia-sama, the conference is beginning.
エミリア様 議会が始まります
中央へ
To the center.
You'll explain this to me later!
絶対に あとでちゃんと
お話するからね
Then, those are the participants
in the royal selection.
（スバル）
つまり あそこにいるのが
王選の参加者
未来の王様候補ってことか
The candidates for the future ruler?
（ラインハルト･
ヴァン･アストレア）
やっぱり君が来たね スバル
You came after all, Subaru.
When I heard Emilia-sama would be here,
エミリア様が
出席されると聞いて―
I suspected you'd be here, as well.
まず 君が
来るんじゃないかと思ったよ
Reinhard, I've been looking for you!
ラインハルト 捜したぜ
Hiya, Subaru-kyun!
（フェリックス）
やっほー スバルきゅん
You...
お前…
（フェリックス）にゃっははー
Oh, Subaru, you know him?
（ラインハルト）
何だスバル 彼とは
知り合いだったのかい？
Huh? "Him"?
“彼”？
Yes. He is a knight, Felix Argyle.
そう
騎士 フェリックス･アーガイル
こう見えて 立派な男性だよ
Despite appearances, he is male.
If you're a guy, what's the point
in having those looks and even cat ears?
（スバル）
そのなりで 猫耳までついてんのに
実は男とか誰得だよ
I don't know what to say.
そんにゃこと言われても―
You're the one who made
the wrong assumption, Subaru-kyun!
勝手に勘違いしたのは
スバルきゅんのほうだしね
Subaru, what's the matter?
スバル 急にどうしたんだい？
Where I'm from, this is the expression
you make when facing a romantic rival!
俺の故郷じゃ
恋敵って虫を見つけたら―
こういう顔をする習わしだ
それでは せん越ながら
近衛(このえ)騎士団 団長の私―
Now, if I may be so forward,
I, Marcos, leader of the Imperial Knights,
マーコスが 議事の進行を
務めさせていただきます
will direct today's proceedings.
事の起こりは 約半年前―
It all happened about half a year ago,
when members of the royal family,
starting with the king,
先王をはじめとする
王族の方々が―
passed away, one by one, causing—
次々とお隠れに
なったことに起因し…
Listen...
（アナスタシア･ホーシン）
あんな 団長さんが―
I get that you wanna talk up a good
show here, but I'm busy, you know.
ビシーっとお話進めたいんは
分かるんやけど―
うちも忙しいんや
As we say in Kararagi, "Time is money."
カララギでは 時間とお金は
価値は一緒やゆうてな…
Wait, a Kansai dialect? Are you kidding me?
If you're just repeating
what we already know,
おいおい 関西弁とかウソだろ
then why did y'all even gather us?
Evidently, everyone in western
Kararagi speaks that way.
（アルデバラン）
西のカララギって国じゃ―
あのなまりが 当たり前らしいぜ
I agree.
（クルシュ･
カルステン）
道理だな
Crusch-sama, should the Karsten
family head say something like that?
（マーコス）クルシュ様
カルステン家の当主が
そのようなことを…
Observing formality is important,
格式を重んじるのは
大事なことだが―
but it is also a fact that our time is limited.
時間が有限であるのも事実だろ
It would be wise to inform
us why we are here at once.
我々が集められた理由に
早々に触れるべきだ
Naturally, I do have a general idea.
もっとも おおよその
想像はついているが
You already know the purpose of this meeting?
（マイクロトフ）
すでに この召集の意味が
分かっておいでですか？
Yes, Lord Miklotov.
ああ マイクロトフ卿
For a drinking party, correct?
酒宴だろ？
One day, we will face each other as rivals.
我々は いずれ競い合う身だが―
But by sharing the same table and drinks,
同じ卓を囲み 杯を交わせば―
we will come to better know one another.
おのずと人柄も知れようと
No, that is not correct.
いや 違いますが
Ferris, this isn't what you told me.
フェリス 聞いた話と違うが
Oh, come on...
やだなー もう
All I said was, "Maybe it'll be a drinking party."
フェリちゃんは
ただ―
酒宴でも 開くのかも
ですねって―
言っただけじゃ
ないですか
I see. I jumped to conclusions.
そうか 私の早とちりか
Forgive me. Allow me to retract what I just said.
すまない
さっきまでの発言は
取り消させてくれ
Hey, now!
Even if she backs down,
my opinion isn't gonna change.
クルシュさんが引いても
うちの意見は変わらんよ
No need to explain the royal selection now.
今から 王選の
うわべのことなんか話さんでも―
We already know.
みんな知ってることや せやろ？
Right?
I think we should hear the—
私は ちゃんとお話は…
Sorry, but I wasn't askin' your opinion.
悪いけど―
うちは あんた様の意見は
聞いてないんよ
Why, you—
（スバル）なっ てめ…
Hey!
（アルデバラン）うははーい
I don't know what's up with the selection,
so I'd kinda like to hear the rest.
王選がどうとか
知らないから―
先が聞きたかったりすっかな
Priscilla-sama, I'm told this man is your knight.
プリシラ様 彼は
あなたの騎士と伺いましたが―
Have you explained the selection to him?
王選の説明は？
Either way, you men will prattle on about it, yes?
妾がせずとも―
長話好きの貴様らが
勝手にするじゃろう？
Continue, Marcos.
続けよ マーコス
Then...
では―
We've gathered you, who are qualified
to be the dragon's priestess,
竜の巫女(みこ)の資格を持つ皆様が
こうして集められたのは―
竜歴石(りゅうれきせき)に新たに刻まれた
予言によるものです
because a new prophecy has been
engraved in the Dragon Stone.
It says, "From the five capable
of becoming the nation's new leader,
そこには 〝新たな国の
導き手になりうる５人〞
choose one priestess to enter
into a covenant with the dragon."
〝その内より
１人の巫女を選び―〞
“竜との盟約に望むべし”と
Five?
５人？
Yes, five.
（ラインハルト）そう ５人だ
Currently, there are only four candidates.
現状 候補者の方々は４人だけ
The royal selection hadn't even begun.
王選は まだ始まってすら
いなかったんだ
But today,
だけど―
history is set in motion.
今日 歴史が動く
Knight Reinhard van Astrea, come forward.
（マーコス）
騎士 ラインハルト･ヴァン･
アストレア ここに
Yes, sir!
Honored members of the council of wise men,
栄誉ある 賢人会の皆様―
I, Reinhard van Astrea, of the Imperial Knights,
近衛騎士隊所属 ラインハルト･
ヴァン･アストレアが―
would like to announce my mission's completion.
任務完了の報告をさせて頂きます
The dragon's priestess, the fifth
and final candidate for the throne,
竜の巫女 王の候補者
最後の５人目―
has been located.
見つかりましてございます
The one I, myself, revere as queen.
自分が 王として仰ぐお方―
Her name...
名を―
is Felt-sama.
フェルト様と申します
Returnto the  Capital